Guide to the William Hillman Shockley Photographs, 1896-1922 and undated, bulk 1897-1909 RL.01177
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- China: Jinchanggouliang, 1897-1898; 207 prints
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0241)
    外国人, 几个中国工人展示淘洗工艺
  - Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0242)
    金厂沟梁
    外国人和几个中国工人展示淘洗工艺
  - Sampling tailings / Chin Chang kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0243)
    矿渣采样，金厂沟梁
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0244)
    Worker pushing a wheelbarrow
    工人推独轮车
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0245)
    Mountain and a village
    山与村庄
    518
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0246)
    Village behind trees
    树林后面的村庄
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0247)
    Workers sitting on rocks
    工人坐在碎石上
    644
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0248)
    People working on hillside
    山腰上忙碌的人们
  - Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, result of panning, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0249)
    淘洗的结果，金厂沟梁
  - Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0250)
    Workers' housing at mine?
  - Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0251)
  - [Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0252)
    Men working in a mine
    工人们在矿场劳作
  - Pay Day, Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0253)
    发薪的日子，金厂沟梁
  - 1st Trip, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0254)
    第一次旅行
  - Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0255)
    Workers resting near a house
    工人们聚在墙边休息
  - Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0256)
    A Westerner and four Chinese resting
    一个外国人和四个中国人在休息
  - Tablet Temple, Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0257)
    庙宇匾额，金厂沟梁
  - End of Waste Dump Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0258)
    废料山尽头，金厂沟梁
  - Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0259.1)
    Chinese overseer (?) standing over two workers, one a boy
    工头？看着两个工人和一个男孩在碎石
  - Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0259.2)
    650
    Duplicate of RL01177-P-0259.1
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0260)
    Man in front of a huge pipe
    一人站在大管道前
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0261)
    Workers squatting over rock pile
    工人们在碎石
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0262)
    A Westerner and two Chinese near a wall
    墙边的外国人和两个中国人
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0263)
    Inside Ma Wang miao - interior of temple
    马王庙内
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0264)
    Workers with mining cart
    工人和运矿的车
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0265)
    Workers and pack horses
    工人和马匹
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0266)
    Mill powered by horse
    马拉磨
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0267)
    Two men and their horses
    两人牵着马
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0268)
    Three people sitting near a wall
    三人坐在墙边
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0269)
    Mountains
    群山
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0270)
    Rocks stored in a room
    屋里堆着的矿石
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0271)
    Children near a rail fence
    围栏旁的几个孩子
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0272)
    Group of women, old man?, and children in distinctive dress
    妇女和孩子们
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0273)
    People and a cart in a yard
    院子里的人们和一辆大马车
    May be Manchuria region.
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0274)
    Group of two Chinese women and many children under a flag
    大人和孩子们
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0275)
    House
    房屋
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0276)
    People and horses in a yard
    大院里的人和马
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0277)
    River or large lake shore with distant figure
    河岸边
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0278)
    512
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0279)
    Men and horse-cart
    人们和大马车
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0280)
    Workers carrying rocks with baskets
    工人筐抬矿石
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0281)
    Chinese worker having foot examined or treated by doctor?
    医生给中国工人治脚？
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0282)
    Chinese man in high-ranking clothing standing on a stone mill
    站在石碾上的男人
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0283)
    Long view of Shockley, Chinese men, and horses in the field
    肖克利和中国人的马队
    Version of RL01177-P-0254
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0284)
    Big tree by water
    河边大树
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0285)
    People and horses in the field
    野外的马队
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0286.1)
    Male child, squatting, without clothes
    赤裸的孩子
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0286.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0286.1
  - Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0287)
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0288)
    River and mountain
    溪流和大山
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0289)
    Shockley in Chinese dress, and three Chinese men
    肖克利着中装和三位中国人
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0290)
    Long view of workers around mine building
    矿场建筑周围的工人们
  - Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0291)
    Chinese man in donkey-cart
    男人在驴车里
  - Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0292)
    Western man in Chinese dress, and three Chinese men
  - Measuring water from mine, Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0293)
    测量矿里的水, 金厂沟梁
  - Grandchild of Ch'u Yü Ch'ee, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0294)
    Ch'u Yu Ch'eu 的孙子
    Older boy holding little boy
    大孩子抱着小孩子
  - Alluvial shaft, Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0295)
    砂矿井，金厂沟梁
  - Sha Kow Gold washing, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0296)
    沙沟?，淘洗金沙
  - 42° 3' N; 119° 41' E / Washing Quartz Gold/ Ch'uan Shan Tzu China, May 22 97, 1897 May 22 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0297)
    [北纬42° 3' ;东经119° 41' / 清洗石英和金砂/ 撰山子，中国5月22日]
    619[?]
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0299)
    A group of men
    一群男人
    180
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0300)
  - The friendly girl, Mongolia, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0301)
    一个友善的女孩, 内蒙古
    Girl with little boy
    女孩抱着小男孩
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0302)
    Woman and two children
    一位妇女和两个孩子
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0303)
    Workers working
    工人在劳作
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0304)
    Temples in the mountains
    大山里的寺院
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0305)
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0306)
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0307)
    Houses on hillside
    山坡上的房屋
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0308)
    People and horses climbing mountain
    马队走在山间
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0309)
    People on a hill
    小山上的人们
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0310)
    Overlooking large settlement
    俯瞰山村
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0311)
    Factories and mountains
    工场和山
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0312)
    People working near a stream
    溪边劳作的人们
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0313)
    Overlooking village
    鸟瞰村庄
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0314)
    Chinese man in wide-brimmed hat walking next to a wall
    一人走在田野
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0315)
    Men blowing on long horns
    吹唢呐的男子
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0316)
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0317)
    Large interior room in Chinese home?
    中国家庭屋内?
    702
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0318)
    People and horse in a yard
    人和马在院内
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0319)
    Men working inside factory
    人们在工场劳作
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0320)
    Shockley and three Chinese at a doorway
    肖克利和三位中国男子站在屋门口
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0321)
    工场
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0322)
    Two men standing next to a small smelter or kiln?
    两人站在一个小矿炉旁
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0323)
    People operating water well
    人们从井里汲水
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0324)
    湖岸
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0325)
    Inside mine factory
    矿场内部
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0326)
    Factory in the mountains
    山间矿场
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0327)
    工人劳作
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0328)
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0329)
    Field with large wall or rampart on hill in background
    田野及远处长长的一道墙堤
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0330)
    People marching down hill
    人们列队下山
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0331)
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0332)
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0333)
    People working in field
    人们在场地上劳作
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0334)
    People in front of large house
    人们站在房前
  - Washing quartz, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0335)
    洗石英
  - Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0336)
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0337)
    Men gathered around with baskets, at mine?
    人们围在篮框周围，矿上？
  - Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0338)
    People working in open-pit mine
    人们在露天矿场地上劳作
  - Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0339)
  - Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0340)
    Distant view of mine factory with stack of bricks in foreground
    地上的砖堆
  - Ku Shan Tzu， Dr. Wang - Shockley, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0341)
    古山子年，王博士 - 肖克利
    Sitting, drinking tea and smoking cigarette
    坐着、喝茶和抽烟
  - Ku Shan Tzu, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0342)
    古山子
    Washing gold
    洗金
  - Washing gold gravel, Mongolia, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0343)
    洗金砂石, 蒙古，1897
  - Chinese soldier / Ch'ing An / asking grace / June, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0344.1)
    "清胡"古山子
    Line of men, kneeling, in turbans and long rifles
    抱着头巾手拿来福枪的一排人
  - "Ch'ing Hu" Ku Shan Tzu, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0344)
    Copy found in Manchuria folder
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0344.1, with different title
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0345)
    Chinese soldiers, with Shockley?
    清兵
  - Ku Shan Tzu, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0346)
    Village on hillside
    山坡上的村子
  - Ku Shan Tzu, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0347)
    Children near a village
    村庄边上的孩子们
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0348)
    Child sitting on ground near sluice?
    小孩坐在地上
  - Stratified Loess near Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0349)
    金厂沟梁附近的黄土坡
    Shockley and others with horses
    肖克利与马队
  - Tailings Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0350)
    矿渣，金厂沟梁
  - Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0351)
  - Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0352)
  - Temple near Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0353)
    金厂沟梁附近的庙宇
  - Near Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0354)
    金厂沟梁附近
    Inside temple
    庙宇内部
  - Alluvial washing, Te Shui ?, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0355)
    淘洗砂矿, Te Shui ?年
    Three workers digging, with overseer above
    三人挖坑，工头在旁
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0356)
    Two men at large round stone gate
    两个男人在月亮门口
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0357)
    Crowd listening to a talk
    众人听讲
  - Dedication of temple, Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0358)
    庙庙捐献，金厂沟梁
  - Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang,Theater Seat for women, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0359)
    金厂沟梁，妇女们看戏时的座位
    652
  - Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0360)
    Crowd gathering in front of theater
    挤在戏台前的人们
  - Theater, Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, March, 1897 March (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0361)
    看戏，金厂沟梁 3月
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0362)
    Theater surrounded by people
    众人观戏
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0363)
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0364)
  - Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0365)
    Theater, temple and large crowd
    戏棚，寺庙和人群
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0366)
    Monks and others inside temple
    寺庙内的僧人和其他人
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0367)
    Monks inside temple
    寺庙内的僧人
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0368)
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0369)
  - God of Infirmities Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0370)
    铁拐李像 金厂沟梁
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0371)
    Figure of a god
    神像
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0372)
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0373)
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0374)
  - God, Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0375.1)
    神像，金厂沟梁
    Monkey god Hanuman?
    猴王哈奴曼？
  - God, Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0375.2)
    Duplicate of RL01177-P-0375.1
  - God, Chin Ch'ang Kou Liang, circa 1897 (Box 2, Print RL01177-P-0375.3)
- China: Manchuria, 1897-1898; 337 prints
  The Manchuria prints form the largest group in the China series, reflecting in part the amount of time Shockley spent in this important mining region. Manchuria has a complex history of occupation by the Chinese, Japanese, Koreans, and Russians, and is now represented by several provinces (Liaoning, Jilin, Inner Mongolia); even today the region around the city of Shenyang ("Moukden") is known for its international population. Because of this, locations and ethnicities in Shockley's images can be difficult to decipher.
  The landscapes of Shockley's Manchuria trip feature mountainous terrain, remote mountain valleys, the Yalu river, and cultivated fields. Captions often document geological features. Places include the Yalu and Hun Rivers; Liao Yang; Willow Palisades; a Manchu emperor's tomb (now in Shenyang's Beiling Park); a Korean house; pagodas, shrines, and temples; a Christian church; and a school. Shockley also photographed the families of Dr. Westwater, a physician and missionary who resided in Liaoyang for many years, and Dr. John Ross, a Scottish Presbyterian physician and missionary living in Shenyang. There is also a portrait of Shockley's servant, Kuei To, and many images of his travel caravan.
  Travel scenes include boat traffic on a river, gravel and lead mining, an iron furnace, a camel train carrying coal, and paying for a fur coat in Shenyang. There are many photographs, casual and portrait, of villagers, workers (both Chinese and Korean), Korean immigrants of all ages, women nursing babies, Chinese soldiers, French priests, and members of Shockley's travel party, as well as the pack animals. There are also numerous images of inns where the travelers stayed. Shockley appears in at least one image, P-0402, on a horse.
  There are many duplicate prints in this series; as with other series, these are indicated by an extension of ".2" after the print identifier.
  - Valley of the Liao near Moukden, 1897 October (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0376.1)
    辽河旁的村落，沈阳附近10月
  - Valley of the Liao near Moukden, 1897 October (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0376.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0376.1
  - Liao yang, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0377)
    辽阳
    Façade of a building
    建筑物前
  - Bridge, Liaoyang, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0378)
    辽阳的桥
  - Main road / Moukden / Newchang, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0379.1)
    主路，沈阳，[牛庄?]
    Mules and wagon mired in mud
    骡子和车陷到泥里面去了
  - Main road Moukden [Newchang?], Manchuria, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0379.2)
    沈阳到牛庄的主路，满州
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0379.1; same event as in RL01177-P-0380
  - Road / Newchang / Moukden, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0380.1)
    路，沈阳，[牛庄?]
  - Manchuria, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0380.2)
    满州
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0380.1; same event as in RL01177-P-0379
  - Tomb at Moukden, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0381)
    陵墓，沈阳
  - Near Moukden, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0382)
    沈阳附近
    Two people in agricultural field
    两个人在耕种
  - Inn at Moukden, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0383)
    沈阳的客栈
  - Inn at Moukden, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0384.1)
  - Inn at Moukden, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0384.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0384.1
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0385.1)
    Woman nursing baby in a doorway
    沈阳大门口给孩子喂奶的女人
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0385.2)
    沈阳 大门口给孩子喂奶的女人
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0385.1
  - Near Yalu River Manchuria, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0386)
    满洲鸭绿江附近
  - Korean house near Yalu R. in Manchuria, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0387)
    鸭绿江附近朝鲜族房子，满洲
  - Manchuria near Yalu, 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0388)
    满洲，鸭绿江附近
  - Yuanch'u Hs [Hsien?], circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0389)
    河滩
  - Ford near Huai Jen Hsien, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0390)
    跋涉在满洲怀仁县 [现桓仁满族自治县]附近
  - Eruptive rock Huai Jen Hsien, Manchuria, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0391)
    火山岩，满洲怀仁县 [现桓仁满族自治县]
  - Manchuria basalt near Kuan Tien Hsien, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0392.1)
    满洲宽甸县附近的玄武岩
  - Near Kuan Tien Hsien / Basalt cliff, Manchuria, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0392.2)
    满洲宽甸县附近的玄武岩峭壁
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0392.1
  - White mountain near Kuan Tien Hsien, Manchuria, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0393)
    满洲宽甸县附近的白山
  - Near Huai Jen Hsien, Manchuria, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0394)
    满洲怀仁县 [现桓仁满族自治县]附近
  - Tuff, Huai Jen Hsien, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0395)
    凝灰岩，怀仁县 [现桓仁满族自治县]
  - Manchuria. Valley of Hun Chuang?, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0396)
    山谷中的Hun chuang， 满洲
  - Iron Mine, Ti Hsuing Shan, Manchuria, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0397)
    铁矿，弟兄山，满洲
  - Lead Mine. Manchuria, 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0398.1)
    铅矿，满洲
  - Lead Mine. Manchuria, 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0398.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0398.1
  - Ti Hsuing Shan, Manchuria, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0399)
    弟兄山，满洲
  - Ti Hsuing Shan Iron?, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0400)
  - Shockley and Kuei To, 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0401)
    肖克利和贵铎
    Kuei To accompanied Shockley's party on this trip and is described in captions as a Chinese servant.
  - Manchuria, 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0402)
    [肖克利和贵铎], 满洲, 1897年
    Shockley on pony
    肖克利骑在马上
  - Manchuria, 4 horned sheep, 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0403)
    四只圈养羊, 满洲
  - Manchuria, 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0404)
    满洲
    Two oxen
    两头牛
  - Manchuria, 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0405)
  - Willow palisades, Pien Wei - Pien Wei, Manchuria, 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0406.1)
    矮桥，Pien Wei - Pien Wei， 满洲
    Willow Palisades were a well-known defensive construction.
  - Should see willow palisades, but none / Pien Li - Pien Wei [the names of the two men on mules?], 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0406.2)
    矮桥 / Pien Li - Pien Wei [坐在骡子上的两人？]
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0406.1
  - Cart, Manchuria, 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0407)
    车，满洲
  - Manchuria, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0408)
    Stream
    溪流
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0409.1)
    Interior of Chinese inn
    客栈的内部
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0409.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0409.1
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0410)
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0411)
    Inn in Manchuria
    满洲的客栈
  - Inn in Manchuria, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0412)
    version of RL01177-P-0411
  - Manchuria, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0413)
    House on mountain
    山上的房屋
  - Manchuria, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0414)
    Back of a woman in the doorway
    门框处背对镜头的妇女
  - Manchuria, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0415)
    Horses, wagon, and people
    马车和人
  - Manchuria, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0416)
    People in a room
    坐在屋里的人们
  - Manchuria, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0417)
    Mountain
    山
  - Manchuria, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0418.1)
    Mountain; caravan
    山；商队
  - Manchuria, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0418.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0418.1
  - Manchuria, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0419)
    version of RL01177-P-0417
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0420.1)
    Close-up of a side railing of a ship
    水上的船只
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0420.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0420.1
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0421)
    version of RL01177-P-0420.1 (cropped)
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0422.1)
    Woman carrying baby with a dog
    背小孩的妇女和一条狗
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0422.2)
    duplicate of RL01177-P-0422.1
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0423)
    Censer in a quad
    庭院中的香炉
  - P'ai Liou Moukden, 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0424)
    沈阳的牌楼
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0425)
    People driving cart
    赶车的人
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0426)
    People with horses
    骑马的人
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0427)
    Westerner with cap and jacket (uniform?) posing in a cemetery with Christian crosses
    外国人
    May be Incheon, Korea - foreigners' cemetery.
  - Camel train from Manchuria bringing coal, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0428)
    从满洲运来煤炭的驼队
  - Chinese soldier Ch'ing An asking grace, 1897 June (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0429)
    中国士兵在行请安礼6月
  - Ai yang (?) Manchuria, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0430)
    爱阳镇，满洲
    Panorama of valley and mountain
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0431)
    Camel train
    驼队
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0432)
    Small female child squatting on a porch
    小孩子蹲在门廊
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0433)
    Group of girls standing in front of a wall
    靠墙站着的女孩们
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0434)
    People standing beside a river
    河边的人们
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0435)
    Western woman standing with back against a column of a brick house
    外国女子背靠廊柱站着
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0436)
    Sheep
    羊群
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0437)
    山岭
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0438)
    Western woman standing on stairs outside a brick house
    外国女子站在屋外的台阶上
    Same woman and house as RL01177-P-0435
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0439)
    Building behind trees
    树后的建筑
  - No known title, circa 1897 (Box 3, Print RL01177-P-0440)